Okay...
The x-tens are online.
Gentlemen, I am now about send a signal
From this laptop through our local isp
Racing down fiber-optic cable at the speed of light
To san francisco, bouncing off a satellite
In geosynchronous orbit to lisbon, portugal,
Where the data packets
Will be handed off to submerged trans-atlantic cables
Terminating in halifax, nova scotia
And transferred across the continent
Via microwave relays back to our isp
And the x-ten receiver attached to this...
Lamp.
Look at me. look at me. I've got goose bumps.
Are we ready on the stereo?
Go for stereo.
Hey, guys.
Hi. hello. hello.
It's a little loud.
No problem-- turning it down.
San francisco, lisbon, halifax...
And voila.
Okay, thanks.
Hang on, hang on. do you not realize what we just did?
Yeah, you turned your stereo down with you laptop.
No, we turned our stereo down by sending a snall
Around the world via the internet.
You know, you can just get one of those universal remotes
At radio shack. they're really cheap.
No, no. You don't get it.
Howard, enable public access.
Public access enabled.
Boy, that's terrific. I'll see ya.
No, hang on, hang on.
See?
No.
Someone in szechwan province, china
is using his computer
To turn our lights on and off.
Well, that's handy.
Here is the question. Why?
Because we can.
They found the remote-control cars.
Well, wait, wait, what's on top of that?
Wireless web cams. wave hello.
The monster truck is out of austin, texas,
And the blue viper is being operated
From suburban tel aviv.
You may want to put on slacks.
What?
Ew, stop it.
No leave me alone
Who's running the red corvette?
That would be me.
The.Cooper.Hofstadter.Polarization
You know, in the future
When we're disembodied brains in jars,
We're going to look back at this as eight hours well wasted.
I don't want to be in a jar.
I want my brain in an android body.
Eight feet tall and ripped.
I'm with you.
I just have to make sure that if I'm a synthetic human,
I'd still be jewish.
I promised my mother.
I suppose you could have your android penis circumcised,
But that's something
Your rabbi would have to discuss with the manufacturer.
Not to mention you'd have to power down on saturdays.
Sheldon, why is this letter in the trash?
Well, there's always the possibility that a trash can
Spontaneously formed around the letter,
But occam's razor
Would suggest that someone threw it out.
It's from the institute for experimental physics.
They want us to present our paper
On the properties of supersolids
At the topical conference on bose einstein condensates.
I know, I read it before I threw it out.
Okay, if I may drill down to the bedrock of my question
Why did you throw it out?
Because I have no interest in standing in the rose room
Of the Pasadena Marriott
In front of a group of judgmental strangers
Who wouldn't recognize true genius
If it was standing in front of them giving a speech.
Which, if I were there, it would be.
I don't know, sheldon.
Those topical conference on bose einstein condensates
Parties are legendary.
Forget the parties.
Forget the parties? what a nerd.
Are there any other honors I've gotten that I don't know about?
Did ups drop off a nobel prize
With my name on it?
Leonard, please don't take this the wrong way,
But the day you win a nobel prize
Is the day I begin my research
On the drag coefficient of tassels on flying carpets.
Ooh, the only thing missing
From that insult was "your mama."
I got one.
Hey, leonard, your mama's research methodology is so flawed...
Shut up, howard.
Sheldon, we have to do this.
No, we don't.
We have to take in nourishment, expel waste,
And inhale enough oxygen to keep our cells from dying.
Everything else is optional.
Okay, let me put it this way, I'm doing it.
You can't. I'm the lead author.
Come on, the only reason you're the lead author
Is because we went alphabetically.
I let you think we went alphabetically
To spare you the humiliation
Of dealing with the fact that it was my idea.
Not to put too fine a point on it,
But I was throwing you a bone.
You're welcome.
Excuse me, I designed the experiment that proved the hypothesis.
It doesn't need proving.
So the entire scientific community
Is just supposed to take your word?
They're not supposed to, but they should.
All right, I don't care what you say,
I'm going to the conference and I'm presenting our findings.
And I forbid it.
You forbid it?
If I'm not taking credit for our work, then nobody is.
So you admit that it's our work? no.
Once again, I'm throwing you a bone.
And once again you are welcome.
Oh, no, he didn't
So, how's it going with sheldon?
Are you guys still not talking to each other?
Not only is he still not talking to me,
But there's this thing he does where he stares at you
And tries to get your brain to explode.
You know, like in the classic sci-fi movie scanners.
Like... bzzz...
Never mind.
How about this one?
It says, I know my physics, but I'm still a fun guy.
Wow, I didn't know they still made corduroy suits.
They don't.That's why I saved this one.
Okay, well, let's just see
What else you have.
Okay, here, take this...
And this, and this, and these...
Is this all stuff you want me to try on?
No, this is stuff I want you to throw out.
Oh. seriously, don't even give them to charity.
You won't be helping anyone.
What's this?
That's the bottle city of kandor.
You see, kandor was the capital city
Of the planet krypton.
It was miniaturized by brainiac before krypton exploded,
And then rescued by superman.
Oh. nice.
It's a lot cooler when girls aren't looking at it.
Here, why don't you put these on
While I find a shirt and a sport coat that match.
Great, I'll be right back.
Where are you going? just put 'em on.
Here?
Oh, are you shy?
No, I'm not shy.
Don't worry. I won't look.
I know you won't look. why would you look?
There's nothing to see... well, not nothing...
Sweetie, put the pants on.
Putting 'em on.
So, you know, isn't there maybe some way
You and sheldon could compromise on this whole presentation thing?
No, no.
Scientists do not compromise.
Our minds are trained to synthesize facts
And come to inarguable conclusions.
Not to mention, sheldon is bat-crap crazy.
What is this?
Oh, careful.
That's my original series
Battlestar galactica flight suit.
Oh, why didn't you wear it on halloween?
Because it's not a costume. it's a flight suit.
Okay, all right, moving on.
Oh, wow, a paisley shirt.
Uh-huh, it goes with my corduroy suit.
If you mean they should end up in the same place, then I agree.
Is this your only tie?
Technically, yes.
But if you'll notice...
It's reversible.
So it works as two.
Oh sweetie, I don't even think it works as one.
Is this all your clothes?
Yup. everything since the eighth grade.
The... the eighth grade?
My last growth spurt.
Okay, well, I guess we're back to the corduroy suit.
Great. yep.
I said no. put it down.
Hey, sheldon.
Hello, penny.
Get anything good?
Just the latest copy of applied particle physics quarterly.
Oh, you know, that is so weird that yours came and mine didn't.
It was a joke.
Yep, tip your waitresses.
I'm here all week.
Penny, just to save you from further awkwardness,
Know that I'm perfectly comfortable with the two of us
Climbing the stairs in silence.
Oh, yeah, okay, me, too.
Zip it, lock it.
Put it in your pocket.
So, you and leonard.
Oh, dear god.
A little misunderstanding, huh?
A little misundersta...?
Galileo and the pope had a little misunderstanding.
Anyway, I was talking to leonard this morning,
And I think he feels really bad about it.
Well, how do you feel?
I don't understand the question.
No, I'm just asking if it's difficult
To be fighting with your best friend.
Oh, I hadn't thought about it like that.
I wonder if I've been experiencing
Physiological manifestations
of some sort of unconscious emotional turmoil.
Wait. what?
I couldn't poop this morning.
Just talk to him.
I'm sure you guys can work this out.
It's certainly preferable to my plan.
Which was?
A powerful laxative.
Okay, so you absolutely should talk to him.
Look, I know leonard values you as a friend,
And he told me himself that without your little idea,
There's no way he could have
Come up with this whole experiment thing.
Excuse me. "little idea"?
Yeah, I mean, he tried to explain it to me.
I didn't really understand it...
Of course, you didn't.
He said, "little idea"?
Well, no, not in... not in those words.
In what words then, exactly?
Um, you know, gee, the exact words...
It's more the spirit in which...
What did he say?
You had a lucky hunch.
Hey, sheldon, I've been thinking.
Instead of arguing about this...
Don't you ever speak to me again.
Wha...?
He...
Okay, I'm leaving for the conference.
Have fun presenting my "lucky hunch."
Shel, I didn't mean it like that.
Then why did you say it?
I don't know. I wasn't...
Were you trying to impress penny?
No, no, not at all. a little bit.
How'd that work out for you?
Leonard, ready to go?
libido 1.0.
Okay, I'm gonna ask you one more time.
We did the work together.
Let's present the paper together.
And I'm telling you for the last time
It's pandering, it's undignified, and bite me.
Let's go.
Bye, sheldon.
Good-bye, penny.
One of these days...
There you go.
You're right. this side does look better.
No, no, I didn't say "better."
I said "less stained."
i just checked the house. there's probably
20-25 people in there.
You're kidding?
Is that all? "all"?
In particle physics, 25 is woodstock.
Oh, well, then good.
I wasn't expecting such a crowd. I'm a little nervous.
It's okay. just open with a joke. you'll be fine.
Uh, joke. okay,
How about this?
Um, okay, uh, there's this farmer,
And he has these chickens,
But they won't lay any eggs, so he calls a physicist to help.
The physicist then does some calculations,
And he says, "i have a solution,
But it only works with spherical chickens in a vacuum."
Right?
Oh, sorry, I just... I've heard it before.
Let's roll. okay.
Hey, nice suit.
It's a classic, right?
I really should have brought my own car.
So, in conclusion, the data show
That at temperatures approaching absolute zero,
The moment of inertia changes,
And the solid becomes a supersolid which clearly appears
To be a previously unknown state of matter.
Thank you.
Were there any questions?
Yeah, what the hell was that?
Any other questions?
Dr. sheldon cooper here.
I am the lead author of this particular paper.
Thank you.
And you, sir, you have completely skipped over the part
Where I was walking through the park,
And I saw these children on a merry-go-round,
Which started me thinking about the moment of inertia
In gases like helium
At temperatures approaching absolute zero.
I didn't skip it. it's just an anecdote.
It's not science.
Oh, I see.
Was the apple falling on newton's head,
Was that just an anecdote?
You are not isaac newton.
No, no, that's true.
Gravity would have been apparent to me without the apple.
You could not possibly be that arrogant.
You continue to underestimate me, my good man.
Look, if you weren't happy with my presentation,
Then maybe you should have given it with me.
As I've explained repeatedly, unlike you,
I don't need validation from lesser minds.
No offense.
So why did you come?
Because I knew you'd screw this up.
I didn't screw it up
Oh, please,
I admit that spherical chicken joke-- that was hilarious. Thanks.
But it was straight downhill from there.
I've had enough of your condescension.
Maybe I didn't go to college when I was 11 like you.
Maybe I got my doctorate at 24 instead of 16,
But you are not the only person
Who is smarter than everyone else in this room
No offense.
And I am clearly not the only person
Who is tormented by insecurity
And has an ego in need of constant validation.
So you admit that you're an egotist?
Yes
My name is dr. leonard hofstadter
And I could never please my parents,
So I need to get all my self-esteem
From strangers like you.
But he's worse
Okay, that is it stop it
You cannot blow up my head with your mind
Then I'll settle for an aneurysm.
Stop it
You hit me
You saw that. he hit me.
You were trying to blow up my head.
So it was working.
It was not you are a nut case
We'll see about that.
Heads up, you people in the front row.
This is a splash zone.
Stop it
Quit it
Is this usually how these physics things go?
More often than you think.
Stop it nerve pinch
You could have offered me a ride home.
You're lucky I didn't run you over.
I really don't understand what you're so unhappy about.
You begged me to come. I came.
There's just no pleasing you.
You're right. I'm the problem.
I'm the one that needs help.
Well, that's not much of an apology,
But I'll take it.
Excuse me.
Is there anything you would like to apologize for?
Yes.
I'm sorry I tried to blow up your head.
It was uncalled for.
You won't believe this.
Somebody got the whole thing on a cell phone
And put it on youtube.
What?
Now who would do that?
That would be me.
Hey, check it out. it's a featured video.
You hit me
You saw that he hit me
You're trying to blow up my head.
So it was working.
Stop it you're a nut case.
We'll see about that.
You people in the front row, heads up. this is a splash zone.
Stop it
Quit it quit it
Put you in a vulcan nerve pinch
Ow, you should cut your fingernails. those hurt
Oh, geez, does this suit really look that bad?
Forget your suit.
Look at my arms waving.
I'm like a flamingo on ritalin.
Howard,
Would you like to explain to me
Why your facebook page has a picture of me sleeping
On your shoulder captioned "me and my girlfriend"?
here comes the talk.
somewhere in China
What losers.
Yeah. Gigantic American geeks.
Who's doing that?
Someone from Pasadena, California named...
"Wolowizard"
Awesome.